

# **Muziwandile Nkomo**

**Nationality:** Zimbabwean (+263) 789844536 **Date of birth:** 18/07/1998

**Gender:** Male **Email address:** <u>muziwandilenko@gmail.com</u>

**Website:** https://muziwandile-portfolio.netlify.app/

in LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/muzi-nkomo-2715701b9/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/muzi-nkomo-2715701b9/</a>

• Address: 4308 Bhejani rd Gwabalanda, 00000 Bulawayo (Zimbabwe)

#### **ABOUT ME**

An experienced Dev Ops Engineer adept at guiding design teams, testing existing software, deploying changes to enhance the IT infrastructure, and assessing and establishing security protocols. I'll find ways to automate manual processes and save the company time and money

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Software developer

**WozaTel** [ 13/05/2019 - 17/10/2020 ]

**City:** Bulawayo **Country:** Zimbabwe

- Built modern applications using MySQL, Java, SQL server, and Spring and supported the company's development and testing processes
- Developed effective microservices and web services and created a series of unit tests to ensure that the projects passed all quality benchmarks
- Worked with a team of expert coders to write maintainable code and maintain existing software to improve performance and fix bugs
- Consulted with clients to identify their projects' specifications and follow up with deployed applications' status and any technical issues
- Developed expertise in CRM and gained trust in clients

## **Devops engineer**

**BushCyber** [ 15/12/2020 - 28/07/2021 ]

City: Pretoria

**Country:** South Africa

- Identified manual processes that could be automated to enhance speed or save money; considered the entire company IT infrastructure when designing improvements
- Monitored and regularly updated essential sections of code; designed, built, and tested proposed changes to existing software
- Oversaw and managed the development, computer coding, testing, and deployment operations of multiple teams
- Assisted with the setup of a cloud-based system and the successful migration of all relevant data
- Prepared systems testing reports for review by upper-level management

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **BSc Computer Science**

National University of Science and Technology [ 14/09/2018 - 14/07/2022 ]

Address: P.O. BOX AC 939 Ascot, 00000 Bulawayo (Zimbabwe)

https://www.nust.ac.zw/

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies

**Final grade**: 2.2 – **Level in EQF**: EQF level 8 **Thesis:** Traffic Sign Detection using Al

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Ndebele

Other language(s):

**English** French

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# My Digital Skills

NoSQL Database MongoDB DynamoDB / Spring (Core, MVC, Spring Data, Batch, Security) / C++ / Linux / Ruby Scripting / Bash-Script / Git / Programming Languages : Python, PySpark, SQL, C, C++, Java, ReactJS

# **Programming Languages**

Java Oracle / Terraforms / Javascript / Python

# **Backend**

Basic - Groovy / Apache, Nginx , Tomcat, Node.js / Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Git, AWS, Selenium, Docker, Kubernetes / Continuous Integration (CI) and deployment (CD) (Jenkins Github Actions GitLab / Containerisation: Docker, Docker-Compose

# **PROJECTS**

## Traffic Sign Detection using Al

[ 13/06/2020 - 17/09/2020 ]

Real time detection of traffic signs using Neural Networks and computer vision. Able to classify 43 different classes of traffic signs from GTSDB in real time

https://github.com/Muzi12345632/TSR-Deploy

## **Reinforcement Learning Ai**

[14/08/2020 - 07/01/2021]

Reinforcement learning is an area of machine learning concerned with how intelligent agents ought to take actions in an environment in order to maximize the notion of cumulative reward. The purpose of reinforcement learning is for the agent to learn an optimal, or nearly-optimal, policy that maximizes the "reward function" or other user-provided reinforcement signal that accumulates from the immediate rewards. Reinforcement Learning also finds application in self-driving cars to train an agent for optimizing trajectories and dynamically planning the most efficient path.

https://github.com/Muzi12345632/Reinforcement\_Learning\_Al